Where are you, Sir Kimblee?!
どこだ  キンブリー殿
話が違う
This is far from what you promised!
You said your soldiers in Briggs would betray the others if we were to carry the attack to the fort!
我々が攻め込めば
必ず ブリッグズから裏切りが出ると…
Cease fire!
撃ち方  やめ～い
That was a crushing victory.
圧勝でしたな
Yeah.
So this...
これが…
...is the bloody crest.
血の紋です
We sigh whenever we're about to come to a standstill
終わりなき旅の途中　立ち止まりそうな時
Owarinaki tabi no tochuu tachidomarisouna toki
While moving on this endless journey.
深いため息こぼす　僕らは
Fukai tameiki kobosu bokura wa
Everytime we lunge for it, it escapes and flies off.
掴みかけてはまた離れていった
Tsukamikaketewa mata hanareteitta
But now, there's nothing to be afraid of
でも今はもう何も恐れることはない
Demo ima wa mou nanimo osoreru koto wa nai
The powerful ties that bind our hearts
心を繋ぐ強い絆は
Kokoro wo tsunagu tsuyoi kizuna wa
Will never come loose.
けして解けはしないさ
Keshite hodoke wa shinai sa
After a lifetime of searching, we finally arrived
探し続けて辿り着いた
Sagashitsuzukete tadoritsuita
Here, where the period lies.
この場所で Period に
Kono basho de piriodo ni
Let's change all our sorrow and rage to power.
悲しみ怒り 力に変えて
Kanashimi ikari chikara ni kaete
Destiny is right within our reach.
運命はすぐそばに
Unmei wa sugu soba ni
だ～から
So I'm saying...
...you're supposed to read the veins of the dragon while performing Eastern Alchemy!
錬丹術は龍脈の流れを読むんですって
だ～か～ら～
And I'm saying...
それが分かんないんだって
...I don't understand how!
You're supposed to sharpen your senses!
感覚を研ぎ澄ませるんですよ
Ready, go!
さん  はい  ほら  感じた
See? I sense it!
I can't do that!
ムリだって
Yes, you can!
できますって
Teach me the theories behind it!
もっと  理論的に教えてよ
にぎやかだねぇ
Things are real rowdy in there.
I don't get it!
Sorry for having to ask you to hide us here.
すまないな  かくまってもらって
Hey, don't worry about it.
気にするな
We're benefiting as well.
こちらも助かってるし
髪はやめろ
Not the hair!
Now the kids have someone new to play with.
子供たちも遊び相手が増えた
Let Zampano know that we're going up to the mountains to collect firewood.
山へ薪を取りに行ってくると
ザンパノにそう伝えてくれ
Sure.
Damn it!
くっそ
What a nightmare!
ひどい目に遭った
Where the hell is Zampano?! Everyone else is working!
みんな働いてるっつうのに
ザンパノの野郎は
どこ行きやがったんだよ
Yo!
This way.
こっちだ  案内する
Follow me.
I'm counting on you, Zampano.
頼むよ  ザンパノ
So, you found out about Selim.
セリムのこと  知ったそうだな
Yes.
はい
And my identity, as well.
私の正体も
Yes.
はい…
How do you feel as a citizen of a country...
国のトップと息子が
人造人間であるというのは
一国民としてはどんな気分かね
...to know that your leader and his son are both Homunculi?
I believe it's a very sad thing for a family member you're supposed to trust to be fabricated.
信ずるべき家族までもが
虚構であるというのは
悲しいことだと思います
It's almost like you're playing house.
家族ごっこです
All the while pretending to be human, creatures you deem as fools.
愚か者とあざける
人間のまねをした…
As you say, he's my "son" given to me by my handlers.
確かに  あれは
上から与えられた息子だ
My rank of Führer President, along with my men and everything else, was also given to me.
大総統の地位も部下も
すべて与えられた
Rather than "house", I'd say it's more accurate to say we're playing "politics".
いわば  権力者ごっこだ
However, I picked my bride myself.
だが  妻だけは自分で選んだ
Is the tea still not ready?
お茶はまだかね
P-Pardon me.
はい
Delicious.
うまい
Wow, so you used to be one of the head honchos of that Research Laboratory 5.
ドクター
あの第五研究所のお偉いさんだったのか
I wouldn't say that. I just had a couple of people working under me.
偉いわけではない
部下が何人かいただけだよ
I wonder how they're doing now...
みんな今ごろどうしているだろうか…
Hey!
Who might that be?
そちらの方は
He's a vagrant I met this morning.
今朝知り合った流れ者だ
He wanted to have you see him, Doctor-
ドクターに診てもらいたいって…
That's enough, Zampano.
もういいよ  ザンパノ
The shitty acting ends here.
三文芝居はここまでだ
こんにちは  ドクター
Why hello, Doctor.
What might you be doing here?
こんな所で何やってんのかな
You're being too optimistic if you think roaches like you can outwit us.
ゴミ虫どもが  我々を
出し抜こうなんて  考えが甘い
What the hell is this?!
なんだこりゃ
Zampano!
ザンパノ
The shitty acting ends here, right?!
三文芝居はもうおしまい  だろ
Our goal from the start was to lure you here!
最初から  貴様をここに
誘い出すのが目的だったのだよ
Knowing how much of a nasty guy you are,
えげつない貴様のことだ
I figured you'd come and hunt me yourself if you knew I was alive!
私が生きていると分かれば
自ら追ってくると思ってね
What can three pieces of trash like you do?!
ゴミ３匹で何ができる
No matter how many you've got on your side,
you're nothing but trash in the end-
何人集まろうが
ゴミはゴミでしか…
They work like landmines.
地雷式だよ
Alchemy evolves every day!
錬金術は日々進化している
There's no way alchemy like that can exist-
そんな錬金術があるわけ…
Dammit!
くっそ～地雷だってんなら…
If they're mines...
...all I have to do is trace your footsteps!
お前たちの足跡をたどれば
引っ掛からないだろ
How can this be?!
なんでだ～
They were made to only react to Homunculi!
人造人間にだけ反応するのだ
You can't tell where they are and what awaits you because of all the snow.
雪のせいでどこに何が
待ち構えているか分かるまい
So, tell me.
どうだ  カスだ  ゴミだと
How does it feel to be ridiculed by people
you've been looking down on as trash and scum?
扱ってきた我々に
なぶり者にされる気分は
He's being fooled, all right.
だまされてますね
It's just remote alchemy.
ただの遠隔錬成ですのに
こっ…この～
You bastards!
You scum should obey our commands, just as you were meant to!
クズはクズらしく
言うことを聞いてりゃいいものを…
You're nothing but trash! Don't get too cocky!
ゴミカスどもが
調子に乗るなよ
Doctor!
ドクター
That was close.
危ねぇ  危ねぇ
Th-Thanks.
すっ  すまない
Grr. You're pretty fast for a fatass.
デブのくせに  素早…
Don't underestimate trash!
ゴミカスをなめるなよ
You little shit!!
くそが～
Such weak attacks can hardly pierce my skin!
こんなしょぼい攻撃効くかよ
Is that so?
そうか
Then what about this ?!
ならば  これでどうだ
Did he do it?!
やったか
Got you now!
捕まえた
ドクター
Doctor!
Whoa, don't move.
おっと  動くなよ
If you do, I'll snap him in half.
ボキッとやっちゃうよ  さて
Now...
...you're in for some punishment.
お仕置きしないとね
言っただろ  ドクター
Didn't I warn you, Doctor?
By saying I'll destroy an entire village if you were to do something unnecessary?
余計なことしたら
村一つ消してやるって
I won't let you!
そんなことはさせん
You're still going to resist?
まだ抵抗するの
Man, you're dumb.
ほんと  バカだね
Okay, I'll destroy those slums over there.
よし
あのスラムをぶっつぶしてやる
Stop!
やめろ…
But simply destroying them is no fun.
ただ  つぶすだけじゃ面白くないな
Perhaps I'll bring a few back to Central and make a philosopher's stone out of them.
何人かセントラルに連れてって
賢者の石の材料にしちゃおうかな
You filth!
貴様…
You're still making those things over at Central?!
まだあそこでそんなものを
作らせているのか
Release the researchers...
研究者たちを…
私の部下を解放しろ
Release my men!
Huh?
That's impossible.
ム～リ
Because you see, we've already turned all of them into philosopher's stones.
だって  あいつら全員
賢者の石にしちゃったもん
E-Even my men?!
私の部下までも…
Oh? Guess I forgot to tell you, huh?
あれ～言ってなかったっけ～
But Doctor, you shouldn't have any reason to weep now , after all this time.
でも  ドクター  今更
悲しむ必要なんてないよね
Since you've made so many philosopher's stones in the past.
だって  今までさんざん
賢者の石を作ってきたじゃないか
Using human lives.
人の命を使ってさ
You're right.
そうだ…
I've made many philosopher's stones, sacrificing the lives of many people.
私は多くの人を犠牲にして
賢者の石を作った
I am more familiar with the ways of making a
philosopher's stone than anyone else in this country.
この国の誰よりも
賢者の石の作り方を知っている
Knowing how to make one...
作り方を知っているということは
...also means I know how to destroy them!!
壊し方も知っているということだ
What on earth is that?!
なんだ  あれ
ドクターたちのいる丘の方からだ
It's coming from the hill where the doctor and the others are!
Oww! Oww!
痛い痛い…痛い  痛い  痛い…
Oww! Oww! Ow! Ow!
No...
嫌だ…
It hurts!
こんな…
This is...
No...
嫌だ…こんな…こんなことが…
This-
This can't be...
このエンヴィーが…
I'm Envy...
There's no way I could be defeated by you inferior beings...
貴様ら下等生物にやられるわけ…
嫌だ…合成獣まで…
No...
Even the chimeras...
見るな…
Don't look at me...
オレを…私を見るな…
D-Don't look at-
Don't look down on me, humans!!!
見下すなよ  人間が～
Don't look at me, you insects...
見るな  虫ケラが…
Little shits...
くそが…見るな…
Don't... look...
We were being manipulated by something like this ?
こんなヤツに
オレたちは踊らされていたのか
We won, Marcoh.
勝ったぞ  マルコー
帰って来た
They're back!
マルコーさん
Doctor Marcoh! What's with that wound?!
どうしたの  そのケガ
それは
What's that ?
Wow, so you guys were doing some amazing things without us knowing.
知らない間に  そんな
すごいことやっていたのか
人間様に逆らうから
This is what happens when you disobey us humans!
こうなるのだ
この  この
マルコーさん
Why did you do something so reckless, Doctor Marcoh?
なんでそんなムチャなことを…
All my life, I've been doing everything as ordered.
私は今まで
言われるがまま動いてきた
But this was the one thing I wanted to settle myself.
だが  これだけは
自分でケリをつけたかったんだ
Thinking on my own... Making a decision on my own...
自分で考えて  自分で決めて…
君のご両親のように
Just like your parents did things.
でも  やっぱりムチャはしないで
But please, try not to be so reckless.
Okay.
Oww!!
痛ぁ～
Ow! Ow! Ow! Ow! Ow!
痛たたたっ
ヨキさん
Sir Yoki?
H-Help me...
たっ  助けて…
こいつの体は頂いた
I've taken over this guy's body!
Stop!
ややっ  やめろ～化け物
You monster!
かっ  体が言うこと聞かない
M-My body isn't listening to me!
ムダ  ムダ
No use putting up a fight!
Now, you trash!
さあ  お前たち
こいつを助けたかったら…
If you want to help this guy...
いや  好きにしていいぞ
Nah, you can do whatever you want with him.
そいつ  仲間じゃないしな
He's not really our friend, anyway.
It's been a short while, Sir Yoki...
ヨキさん  短いおつきあいでした
I'll never forget you!
君のことは忘れないよ
傷のだんな  だんなは
Master Scar!
You're  on my side though, right?!
私の味方ですよね  ねっ
Right?!
Don't look away, dammit!!
目ぇそらすな  こら～
I believed in you, Master!
なっ  なんで
W-What? I thought this guy was your friend!
こいつ仲間なんじゃあ…
I believed in you!
無駄なことはするな  エンヴィー
Quit putting up a useless fight, Envy!
At this point, we don't exactly care about our actions.
もはや  なりふり構っている
我々ではない
邪魔するなら
If you're going to get in our way,
we'll destroy you along with that man!
その男の体ごと滅ぼすぞ
Dammit...
くそ…
He came off.
取れた
Really?
ほんと
ナ～イス演技
Nice act.
I-I'm not very good at bluffs...
ハ…ハッタリとか
得意じゃないんだよ
Damn you all!
ちくしょ～
貴様らなんて  友達じゃないやい
None of you are my friends!
絶交だ  縁  切ってやる
Our friendship is over!
I have nothing to do with you anymore!
Damn...
くっそ～…
じゃあ  そろそろ
So, it's about time you tell us what you guys are up to.
お前らの計画について
聞かせてもらおうか
Like I'll tell you.
知らないね
What did you say?!
なん～～だと  こらぁ
Spill it!
吐け  吐きやがれ  虫ケラ野郎
Spill the beans, you insect!
Keep it up!
いけ  やっちまえ  ザンパノ
Show him who's boss, Zampano!
吐いたら
If I tell you, I'll just be killed later!
あとは殺されるだけじゃねぇか
Why would I tell you, idiots?
誰がしゃべるか  バ～カ
くっそ～
You son of a...
そういえば
Oh yeah, where's the Fullmetal runt?
鋼のおチビさんはいないのか
Brother?
兄さん
He should be in Briggs right now.
今はブリッグズにいるはずだよ
Oh?
Last I heard, he was missing.
オレは行方不明って聞いてるけど～
何それ
What?!
どういうこと  詳しく
What do you mean?!
Tell me more!
バズクールで
I heard a mine collapsed in Baschool.
坑道が崩落したらしいからね～
I wonder if he's alive...
生きてるかな～
No way...
そんな…うそ…
That can't be true.
どうする
So, what should we do?
いったん  バズクールへ戻るか
Should we head back to Baschool?
いや  兄さんなら  こういうとき
No.
In a situation like this...
...Brother would definitely believe in the safety of the other team and keep moving forward.
きっと相手の無事を信じて
前に進もうとするはず
だから  僕らも前へ進もう
So I want to do the same.
希望はまだある
Hope is not lost.
オレは一度別行動を執る
I'm going to split off for a bit.
I've been thinking about it for a little while now.
少し前から考えていたことだ
イシュヴァールを否定した
Instead of simply detesting this country for denying Ishbal...
この国をただ憎むのではなく
変えるために
...I'm going to work to change it.
And for that, I need your help as well, Marcoh.
そのためにはマルコー
お前の力も必要だ
Sure.
分かった  一緒に行こう
I'll go with you.
To change this country...
この国を変えるため…
The thing is, there's a city I want to visit, as well.
実は僕も
ちょっと行きたい町があるんだ
どこだよ  それ
Where?
リオールって町
Lior.
予想どおりなら  そこにも
If my predictions are correct, that tunnel should be there, too.
あのトンネルがあるはずだ
May, take this thing and return to your country.
So I'm thinking it'll be fastest for us to just destroy that.
メイ  お前はこれを持って国へ帰れ
Then, we'll be able to buy time.
Hey, Master!
ちょっと  だんな…
It's the wreck of an immortal homunculus.
殺しても死なない
With the extra time, we can solve the structure of the new transmutation circle.
人造人間の成れの果てだ
With this, your clan may be saved.
これで  お前の一族が助かるかもしれん
So, this "new transmutation circle" is the thing we discovered the other day, right?
B-But if I go back, who'll be here to help you with Eastern Alchemy-
でっ  でも
私が帰ったら  錬丹術のことが…
Yup, that's the one.
人の国に構っている場合か
Is this really the time to be worrying about another country?!
Did you come to this country with a resolve that weak?
そんな覚悟でこの国に来たのか
もし  権力争いに負けたら
If your clan happens to lose its struggle for power,
what are you going to tell the people who placed their fate in your hands?
お前は命運を託してくれた者たちに
"I failed because I was too busy helping people from another country"?!
よその国に構ってて
助けられなかったと言い訳するのか
行け  この国のことは
Go.
We, the citizens of this country, will take care of it ourselves.
この国の人間でなんとかする
ありがとう…ございました
Thank you... so much!
メイ  元気でね
Take care, May.
錬丹術  ひと段落したら
Once we settle things here, I'll visit you to learn more about Eastern Alchemy.
また学びに行くよ
Sir Al...
アル様…
Sir Al!
アル様  メイは…メイは…
I... I...
Thank you so much, everyone!
皆さ～ん  本当にありがとう
Good bye!
さようなら～
Take care!
元気でね～
She's gone...
行っちゃったね
Yeah.
それじゃあ  我々も
Well then, we should get going, as well.
Right.
Mr. Greed...
グリードさん…
No luck.
だめだ  イズミ·カーティスは
Apparently, Izumi Curtis is out on vacation with her husband, and no one knows when they'll be back.
だんなと旅行に行っていて
いつ戻るか分からんらしい
Guess there's not much we can do.
しかたない
いったん  ブラッドレイ大総統のところへ
We should head back and report this to Führer President Bradley for now.
報告しに戻るか
ブラッドレイ
Bradley?!
一緒に来てもらうぞ  グリード
You're coming with me, Greed.
代わりの者をよこしてもらおう
Call someone to take over.
Good idea.
そうだな
あいつらについていけば
I might be able to see Mr. Greed if I follow them...
グリードさんに…
でも…
But...
あの…
Umm...
足をどけていただけませんか
Would you mind moving your foot, Sister?
姉上…
You are to address me as "Major General" here!
ここでは少将と呼べ
Aye, ma'am!
アイ…マム…
相変わらず  ふぬけた面をしおって
You've got a cowardly face on as always, I see.
I heard the battle with Drachma ended with your crushing victory.
さ…先のドラクマ戦では
圧勝であったとか
当たり前だ
Of course!
国土錬成陣が完成してしまうのでは
But wouldn't that just speed up the completion of the Nationwide Transmutation Circle?
It doesn't matter.
かまわん
What we must protect right now is the safety of the country itself.
今我らにとって守るべきは
この国の安寧
それを一瞬たりとも脅かす敵あらば
If there stands an enemy who threatens that very peace...
...our job is to deliver an overwhelming defeat of perfection!
圧倒的で  完ぺきな敗北を
与えてやらねばならん
いやはや  まっこと猛々しい
Oh dear... why must you act so fierce?
これではいつまでたっても
At this rate, you'll never find someone to marry-
嫁のもらい手が…
You just lack the fighting spirit!
お前は闘争心が足らんのだ
グズが
You laggard!
Being with you makes me feel cowardly as well!
お前といると臆病がうつるわ
ここにいたか  少将
There you are, Major General.
He's your brother, I take it?
弟かね
弟と思いたくありませんな
I don't even want to think of him as my brother.
イシュヴァールから
He's a coward who ran away from Ishbal.
逃げ帰るような臆病者
Follow me.
来なさい
There's something I'd like to show you.
見せておきたいものがある
国家錬金法の三大制限を知ってるかね
Are you aware of the three laws state alchemists are forbidden to disobey?
If I recall...
確か 「軍に逆らうな」
"Do not oppose the military."
「金を作るな」 「人をつくるな」
"Do not make gold."
And "Do not create humans."
だったかと
Precisely.
そのとおり
The first law is self-explanatory.
「軍に逆らうな」は言わずもがな
「金を作るな」は
The second law is put in place to avoid economic turmoil.
経済の混乱を避けるため
Then what about the third?
では 「人をつくるな」は
Why does the nation forbid alchemists from creating humans?
なぜ国家は人をつくることを禁止している
倫理にもとるからでしょう
I assume it's because of the moral and ethical implications.
錬金術師らの間でも
Even among alchemists, I hear the act is tacitly forbidden as a blasphemy to God.
神への冒とくと
暗黙のうちに禁じられていると聞きますし
You're wrong there.
違うな
What is and is not ethical changes with time and also depends on whom you ask.
倫理などというのは
時代や個人によって変わるものだ
That is not the reason.
理由はそんなものではない
個人が強力な軍隊を
It is to prevent an individual from creating a powerful army of their own, Major General.
持たぬようにするためだよ  少将
The promise we never made
交わしたはずのない約束が
Kawashita hazu no nai yakasoku ga
yet again
今日も
Kyou mo
tries to snatch our future away from us.
僕らの未来を奪おうとする
Bokura no mirai wo ubaou to suru
Why is it that we can't rejoice
欲しがっていたものを手にしても
Hoshigatteita mono wo te ni shitemo
straight from the heart
素直に
Sunao ni
when we obtain something we've always been after?
うまく笑えないのはなぜだろう
Umaku waraenai nowa nazedarou
The overflowing tears aren't from feebleness or remorse.
あふれる涙は　弱さや後悔じゃない
Afureru namida wo yowasa ya koukai ja nai
They're fragments born from agony.
イタミが生んだカケラで
Itami ga unda kakera de
Of all the moments and destinies,
どんな瞬間だって運命だって
Donna shunkan datte unmei datte
I realized there's one absolute certainty.
ひとつだけ確かなものがあると知った
Hitotsu dake tashika na mono ga aru to shitta
Even if things get tough and I'm at my limit
限界だって困難だって
Genkai datte konnan datte
I refuse to give up.
あきらめたくないよ
Akirametakunaiyo
Please, don't let go.
このまま離さないで
Konomama hanasanaide
I can feel the warmth of your right hand
かたく握りしめた　君の右手のぬくもり
Kataku nigirishimeta kimi no migite no nukumori
where it's tightly joined with my left.
ここにあるから
Koko ni arukara
This place is in ruins...
ひでぇな  こりゃ
こんな所に飯食える所があるのか
Is there really a place to eat around here?
Let's see... I know it was around here somewhere...
え～っと  確か  この辺に…
ロゼ  元気だった
Rose!
How have you been?!
アルこそ
I should be asking you the same thing, Al!
なぁに  まだ旅してるの
What, you're still on a journey?
なんだ  知り合いか
Oh, you know her?
Yeah, something like that.
まあ ちょっと
Al, where's Ed?
アル
エドは  一緒じゃないの
He's not with you?
B-Brother isn't with us today.
にっ  兄さんは
今日はいないんだ
そう  残念ね
Oh... that's too bad.
I really wanted to see him.
すごく会いたかったのに
What's this?
Wh-What?!
何よ
いや～その微妙な顔は
No, I was just pondering the meaning behind that mysterious look on your face.
何かと思いまして
変なこと言わないでよ
Quit saying weird things!
Hey, Rose!
ロゼ
鍋  洗い終わったよ～
I finished washing the pots!
ほかに仕事…
Is there anything else for me to-
再会  復活  決意
日本語字幕仕上げ：XIAOBIN
Reunion. Revival. Resolve.
魂を燃やすときは来た
The time has come to set the soul afire.
漫遊字幕組
http://popgo.net/bbs
生きているかぎり
As long as they live, humans continue to move forward.
人は進み続けるのだ
たとえ  どんなに
No matter how thorny the path may be.
つらい道のりだとしても
Next time, Fullmetal Alchemist:
次回　鋼の錬金術師
Fullmetal  Alchemist
第４４話　『バリンバリンの全開』
Episode 44, Revving at Full Throttle.
目覚めよ  人間
Awaken, human.
Now is the beginning.
今こそ  始まりのとき